{
  "1": {
    "question": "What is the primary use of the Node.js platform?",
    "options": [
      "Developing mobile applications",
      "Building web servers",
      "Creating desktop applications"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Building web servers"
  },
  "2": {
    "question": "What is the purpose of the 'require' function in Node.js?",
    "options": [
      "To define a new variable",
      "To import modules",
      "To execute asynchronous functions"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "To import modules"
  },
  "3": {
    "question": "Which of the following best describes the event loop in Node.js?",
    "options": [
      "A mechanism for handling HTTP requests",
      "A data structure for storing event listeners",
      "A mechanism for managing asynchronous operations"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "A mechanism for managing asynchronous operations"
  },
  "4": {
    "question": "What is a callback function in the context of Node.js?",
    "options": [
      "A function that is executed after a database query completes",
      "A function that is called when an error occurs",
      "A function that is passed as an argument to another function and is invoked later"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "A function that is passed as an argument to another function and is invoked later"
  },
  "5": {
    "question": "What is npm in Node.js?",
    "options": [
      "Node Package Manager",
      "Node Process Manager",
      "Node Package Module"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Node Package Manager"
  },
  "6": {
    "question": "Which module in Node.js provides utilities for working with file paths?",
    "options": [
      "path",
      "fs",
      "util"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "path"
  },
  "7": {
    "question": "What is the purpose of the 'fs' module in Node.js?",
    "options": [
      "To interact with the file system",
      "To create web servers",
      "To perform mathematical operations"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "To interact with the file system"
  },
  "8": {
    "question": "What does the term 'middleware' refer to in the context of Node.js?",
    "options": [
      "Software used for testing",
      "Functions that have access to the request and response objects",
      "A type of database management system"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Functions that have access to the request and response objects"
  },
  "9": {
    "question": "What is the role of the 'Buffer' class in Node.js?",
    "options": [
      "To handle network communication",
      "To manipulate binary data",
      "To manage database connections"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "To manipulate binary data"
  },
  "10": {
    "question": "Which HTTP module in Node.js is commonly used to create web servers?",
    "options": [
      "http",
      "url",
      "querystring"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "http"
  }
}
